<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>6degrees</title>
    <description>6degrees is the self-updating phonebook that helps you verify your friends&#39; details, cleans duplicates, integrates your social networks and backs itself up.
</description>
    <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.get6degrees.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 19:56:11 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 19:56:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Those annoying multiple copies of contacts on your phone!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I visited China to speak to local technology companies about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;6degrees&lt;/a&gt;. Landing there, I was quite apprehensive about many issues I was expecting to face. This was my first trip to China, and apart from being a vegetarian guy used to 30 degrees Celsius (local temperature was 8 degrees), I also didn’t speak Chinese. My co-founder Arun and I considered 6degrees to be quite an involved concept, and I was unsure if the Chinese market would accept the use case we were offering to them. The challenge: To clearly communicate to them the problems we were trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And immediately, there was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day one, NOBODY I met understood English. My carefully-rehearsed pitch, despite me speaking as slowly and in as simple words as possible, was a disaster. I was met with blank faces. For the afternoon, I managed to hire an interpreter for the afternoon with the organizers’ help, but she got stuck in traffic, and when she finally reached the venue at 4:30 pm, I was already counting my losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then something happened. A change of plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our next session, I decided to go straight to the demo. And I started with how we were helping people delete their duplicate contacts. I showed the audience how 6degrees organizes their duplicate contacts into sets, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/others-duplicates_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Duplicate Contacts Displayed&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block; &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and from there, how they can simply tick them and merge/delete them, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/post3_duplicates1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Choose the duplicates Merge/Delete them&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose the duplicates and merge/ delete them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tell immediately that we’d got the audience’s attention. That we were solving a problem that mattered to them. I spent th next two hours answering enthusiastic questions (through the interpreter, of course) about what else 6degrees could do – our Live network of phonebooks, our Search feature, and our plans for an inbuilt yellow-pages feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day was a reminder to me of the power of technology, and ultimately of how similar people are across the world, in many small ways – here I was, a complete stranger from another culture, on my first visit to one of the most enigmatic countries on the tech map, and I realized how the problems that we in the English-speaking world have, find an equal resonance among people from China. It was a good reminder, and I felt motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How 6degrees treats your duplicates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicates are basically of two types – 1) Identical duplicates, where two contacts have the exact same number of fields, and the exact same values for each field, and 2) non-identical duplicates, where two contacts belong to the same friend of yours, but contain one or more different fields/ values. These are caused by several factors, the most common being several invasive apps on your own phone that add duplicates to your contact list. The 6degrees app has a “Delete Duplicates” feature at the bottom of your contacts list, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/1-contacts_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;The [X] icon at the bottom helps you view/delete duplicates&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you click on that icon, the 6degrees app takes a few seconds to arrange your duplicates into sets for you to see. Identical duplicates are easy to deal with – 6degrees deletes all but one copy of each of those, so you are left with one copy of each identical set. The non-identical duplicates are then displayed in a clear form (see the first image above) for users to play with.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 21:53:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/11/AnnoyingDuplicates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/11/AnnoyingDuplicates.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
