<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>6degrees</title>
    <description>6degrees is the self-updating phonebook that helps you verify your friends&#39; details, cleans duplicates, integrates your social networks and backs itself up.
</description>
    <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.get6degrees.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:46:31 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2014 16:46:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>She searched for a cafe nearby. What happened next will blow your mind.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/YellowPages_Beautiful_Girl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beautiful girl&quot; style=&quot;width: 200px;height:301px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you clicked on this post just because of the headline and the pretty girl’s picture, click-baiting works! Sorry. Hopefully, the rest of this post will be worth your click. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Finding a cafe on a friend&#39;s phone:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered which restaurants your friends like? Ever wanted to ask your friends for reommendations for the best plumber nearby, or maybe a good gym to go to? With &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;6degrees&lt;/a&gt;, you can search your these and find results - on your friends’ phones. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re saying is: don’t be boring - don’t just Google for what you want. Ask your friends. It’s more fun that way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you have awesome places, shops and people on your phonebook, share them with your trusted friends and family - when people discover good places because of you, you’re the hero!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What about Privacy?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, your friends need to give you access - if they trust you, they will connect to you on 6degrees. And as described in our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/10/11/PeopleSearch.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, they can decide which contacts from their 6degrees phonebook are accessible to you. Besides - you can’t just open a particular friend’s contact list and go through it - you have to search for a specific thing that you are looking for. Like “cafe” or “Dr”. Here’s what you’ll see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/YellowPages_CafeSearch.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cafe Search on 6degrees&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Get the details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can either click on the “Contacts of Contacts” category to view cafes on your friends’ phones, or click on “Nearby Places” to view cafes located near you. Remember to switch on your phone’s location-sharing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, we’re showing you these nearby places using Google’s Places feature. But soon, there will be more listings here from local partners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn exactly how to request a cafe’s details from a friend’s phone in the “Contacts of Contacts” category, read our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/10/11/PeopleSearch.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why we&#39;re doing this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This yellow-pages-like feature in 6degrees was born from our belief that your personal network isn’t just about family &amp;amp; friends - it includes other people who provide little services to you on a daily basis, and whom you might need at any time - your driver, your plumber, or a restaurant near your house. But most of these are unknown to us, and we often discover these through our network - our friends. That’s what we’re trying to unshackle - the power of your network. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: Headline picture of young woman found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://thechive.com/2012/06/12/beautiful-girls-40-photos/simply-beautiful-34/&quot;&gt;thechive.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 20:20:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/11/01/YellowPages.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/11/01/YellowPages.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>features</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A whole new way of finding new friends - through old ones</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article attempts to show you something awesome - the people-finder feature on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;6degrees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; style=&quot;padding-bottom:20px;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/PeopleSearch_SearchVideo.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; /&gt;
Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we were designing the search feature on 6degrees, we wanted to make something that would allow you, the user, to share your entire network of connections with people whom you trust - usually family, friends and good acquaintances - in return for access to theirs. While no contact details (phone numbers/ email addresses) are displayed, your friends can search for specific people and see whether they are on your phonebook. At the same time, you can hide any (or all) contacts on your phone’s contact list from being searchable - this is explained later in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sign in to 6degrees, your contacts list will look like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/1-contacts_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;6degrees Contacts List&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people in the “Live” section above your phone contacts are your Live Contacts - basically your friends who are on 6degrees already. The more friends you have on 6degrees, the more Live Contacts you have, and you will be able to access these people’s contacts that aren’t hidden. Similarly your Live Contacts can search for specific people on your contacts list - the ones that aren’t hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Search for someone:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click on the search button on the top right and search for someone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/PeopleSearch_SearchResults.png&quot; alt=&quot;Search Results&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, 6degrees gives you results not only from your own phonebook (your 1st-degree contacts, at the bottom) but also from Contacts of your contacts (2nd-degree - from your Live Contacts’ phonebooks) and from everyone else on 6degrees (3rd degree and above). In addition, there’s a fourth category - Nearby Places. This will be the subject of a future blog post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Contacts of your Contacts:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if I click on the “Contacts of your contacts” category, I can see all the guys out there called “John” who are connected to me through at least 1 mutual friend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/PeopleSearch_CoC_ResultsList.png&quot; alt=&quot;Contacts of your Contacts - Results&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The numbers on the right show the number of mutual contacts (Live Contacts) that I share with that person. If I click on John Alderson here, the below is what I see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/PeopleSearch_JohnAlderson.png&quot; alt=&quot;John Alderson&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I can’t see any contact details here, because I’m not connected to John Alderson yet, but I can request my mutual friends (below) for his contact. They will get a notification and can say Yes or No. If they say Yes, I will get John’s contacts, and he will get a notification saying I have received his contact from his friend (if John is a 6degrees user). Remember - I cannot choose a Live Contact of mine (such as Anthony Jacobs here) and go through his contacts to see whom I know. I have to search for a specific person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Hide your secret contacts from others on 6degrees:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if Anthony or Chloe do not want me or anyone else on 6degrees to know that John’s contact is on their phone, they can easily hide him. You can do this easily from your main contacts list by pressing the Edit (pencil) button at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/PeopleSearch_EditMode.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hide Contacts&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can tick your secret contacts here and press the “Lock” button at the bottom. These contacts will no longer be visible to others in search results. In fact, you can even press the “Select All” button at the bottom and hide all your contacts this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s how you use the People Search feature on 6degrees - go ahead and give it a try. You’ll be surprised by what you’ll discover about your personal network.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 20:00:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/10/11/PeopleSearch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/features/2014/10/11/PeopleSearch.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>features</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ever lost your contacts because you lost your phone?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post deals with one of man’s deepest fears in the modern era - losing or damaging his phone, and hence losing all his contacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the unique things about phone contacts, compared to other “social” platforms, is that they are always growing, and that too organically. People don’t “stalk” others and add them on their phonebook the way they do on LinkedIn or Facebook - you meet someone, you care enough to stay in touch, and you exchange contact information. This interaction forms the atom, the smallest building block, of your phonebook. When I bought my first phone, it had zero contacts. That’s never happened again. 10 contacts went to 50, and to 100, and to 500. Today I have more than 1600 contacts. It only grows. We rarely delete people contacts from our phonebook. And it’s not just the contacts that we care about - it’s also the favourites, the recent calls - the whole package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second distinguishing feature of the “organic” phonebook is that people will go to great lengths to preserve the information there. When we change phones, we use external software, often paid apps, to move contacts across platforms. Some people pay for online storage because they don’t trust the free ones. You never hear someone saying, “I’m going to log off my phonebook now - it takes up too much of my time”, unlike “social” networks, where users often delete their account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given how important, and increasingly big, the phonebook is - we decided we’d make it a little easier for people to move from one phone to another with an easy, portable phonebook. Here’s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On your existing (old) phone, download and install &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;6degrees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finish the sign-up process and create your own “Live Contact” which will be visible to your friends on 6degrees. You can currently sign up through your own email ID and password, or through Facebook or Google+ (a.k.a social signup). The social sign-up page looks like this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/Social_Signup_page.png&quot; alt=&quot;Social Signup page&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block; &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once you’ve signed up, give it a few minutes to identify your “Live” contacts - meaning people on your phonebook (your friends) who are already on 6degrees. This takes a couple of minutes. Once this is done, you will get a notification saying “We have finished searching for your Live contacts”. If you do have friends on 6degrees, you will see a non-zero number on the top right, in the “Live” bar, like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/Post-sync_coach_mark1.png&quot; alt=&quot;6degrees Contacts after Live&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On your new phone, download 6degrees and sign in using the same email ID and password, or using the same social network (facebook or Google+) as your old phone. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. You will see the exact same Contacts List on your new phone now. Not only that, all your favourites, recent calls etc will also be visible exactly as in your old phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/1-contacts_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;6degrees Contacts on new phone&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool thing is - you no longer NEED to use your native phonebook on your phone. Drag 6degrees into the place on your homescreen where your existing native phonebook is - it does everything that your existing phonebook does, and more! 6degrees can be your new phonebook. And your contacts are no longer dependent on your device.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2014 18:37:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/21/BackUpPhonebook.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/21/BackUpPhonebook.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Those annoying multiple copies of contacts on your phone!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I visited China to speak to local technology companies about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;6degrees&lt;/a&gt;. Landing there, I was quite apprehensive about many issues I was expecting to face. This was my first trip to China, and apart from being a vegetarian guy used to 30 degrees Celsius (local temperature was 8 degrees), I also didn’t speak Chinese. My co-founder Arun and I considered 6degrees to be quite an involved concept, and I was unsure if the Chinese market would accept the use case we were offering to them. The challenge: To clearly communicate to them the problems we were trying to solve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And immediately, there was a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the morning of day one, NOBODY I met understood English. My carefully-rehearsed pitch, despite me speaking as slowly and in as simple words as possible, was a disaster. I was met with blank faces. For the afternoon, I managed to hire an interpreter for the afternoon with the organizers’ help, but she got stuck in traffic, and when she finally reached the venue at 4:30 pm, I was already counting my losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then something happened. A change of plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our next session, I decided to go straight to the demo. And I started with how we were helping people delete their duplicate contacts. I showed the audience how 6degrees organizes their duplicate contacts into sets, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/others-duplicates_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Duplicate Contacts Displayed&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block; &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and from there, how they can simply tick them and merge/delete them, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/post3_duplicates1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Choose the duplicates and Merge/Delete them&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose the duplicates and merge/ delete them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could tell immediately that we’d got the audience’s attention. That we were solving a problem that mattered to them. I spent the next two hours answering enthusiastic questions (through the interpreter, of course) about what else 6degrees could do – our Live network of phonebooks, our Search feature, and our plans for an inbuilt yellow-pages feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That day was a reminder to me of the power of technology, and ultimately of how similar people are across the world, in many small ways – here I was, a complete stranger from another culture, on my first visit to one of the most enigmatic countries on the tech map, and I realized how the problems that we in the English-speaking world have, find an equal resonance among people from China. It was a good reminder, and I felt motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How 6degrees treats your duplicates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Duplicates are basically of two types – 1) Identical duplicates, where two contacts have the exact same number of fields, and the exact same values for each field, and 2) non-identical duplicates, where two contacts belong to the same friend of yours, but contain one or more different fields/ values. These are caused by several factors, the most common being several invasive apps on your own phone that add duplicates to your contact list. The 6degrees app has a “Delete Duplicates” feature at the bottom of your contacts list, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/1-contacts_play_store_screenshot_2-5.png&quot; alt=&quot;The [X] icon at the bottom helps you view/delete duplicates&quot; style=&quot;width: 167px;height:297px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time you click on that icon, the 6degrees app takes a few seconds to arrange your duplicates into sets for you to see. Identical duplicates are easy to deal with – 6degrees deletes all but one copy of each of those, so you are left with one copy of each identical set. The non-identical duplicates are then displayed in a clear form (see the first image above) for users to play with.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 21:53:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/11/AnnoyingDuplicates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/09/11/AnnoyingDuplicates.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Serendipity and geometry decided our startup’s name and logo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It was a hot, sweaty December mid-morning in Singapore last year, when Arun and I took a bus to the nearby Starbucks to meet a large cloud solutions provider. We were happy with our existing setup but exploring newer, better options. We had a lengthy meeting full of technical discussions and business outlook, along with our product demo and description. We didn’t really get what we were looking for from the guy, and it was clear about 5 minutes in, that the meeting would be a wipeout. We enjoyed the coffee (and the air-conditioning), but as we got up to leave, the guy said something that made the meeting unforgettably impactful for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is great, what you guys are doing - it’s like the seven degrees of separation, you know. Everyone can see how they are related to friends’ friends. It’s cool.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even as I mentally corrected him in my mind from 7 to 6, Arun and I instantly knew what we were going to call our product. We’d been looking for a new name for a while (we used to call it Livebook internally earlier, before we made it public) and all our naming ideas had started to sound bad after just a few hours of thinking. I guess it’s a bit like naming a baby - without the gender considerations. You really want to get it absolutely perfectly right. And serendipitously, we’d got our “perfect” name from a total stranger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, serendipity didn’t help us much in our search for a logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any basic google search will tell you, 6degrees is the popular theory originally set out by Frigyes Karinthy and popularized by a play written by John Guare – that everyone and everything is six or fewer steps away, by way of introduction, from any other person in the world. This, in essence is what 6degrees is all about – to be a network of contacts where everyone is connected in some way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin with, we had chosen a name that didn’t directly convey our product’s features (unlike Mcdonald’s burgers, for example). Our choice was subtler, and most people in our circles didn’t know separation theory. However, we could still aim to create a relatively simple logo that didn’t clash with the name, and yet capture the user’s psycho-optical attention. Unlike a Whatsapp, a very simple name that has a chat app screaming from its logo itself, we were more like a Firefox - a more attractive name, which simply translated the attractiveness of the name to the logo. This post is not to justify our choice or to write a how-to - it is merely our story. There are often multiple correct answers in such situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our designer Aen, who I think is hands-down the best UX guy in Singapore, accepted our simple principles and allowed his sense of geometry to do the magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mathematical constructs in the logo’s geometrical form are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continuity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hexagon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equilaterals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of placing the degree symbol in an arbitrary position, he used the ascender of the 6 as the guide and placed it along the outer curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/6degrees_logo_construction_gif.gif&quot; alt=&quot;6degrees logo - stepwise geometric construction&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;height:375px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The counter of the 6 is also placed in the same continuum as the ascender in a configuration similar to the Large Hadron Collider which accelerates protons from the smaller circle into the large circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/Location_Large_Hadron_Collider.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Large Hadron Collider&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px;height:400px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hexagon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being six-sided, the hexagon is the perfect polygon to communicate the concept of six degrees of separation. The hexagon is also one of the most efficient shapes in nature. Bees instinctively construct their hives as three-dimensional hexagons because they make for robust structures that cost the least wax. Since 6degrees is very much about maintaining a clean and efficient contact list, having a hexagonal frame makes sense.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/6degrees_on_hexagon.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hexagon&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;height:375px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graphite is made up of layers of graphene, each a single atom thick. In graphene carbon atoms are arranged in a hexagonal grid. Carbon nanotubes which are essentially rolled up tubes of graphene owe their strength to this hexagonal nature.
Equilaterals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hexagons have internal angles of 720°. Each vertice is 120°. A hexagon can be sliced into six equilateral triangles. Each one can be half into two right-angle triangles. Overlaying the hexagon over the outer circle, he broke it into twelve equal parts.
&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com/assets/6degrees_equilaterals.png&quot; alt=&quot;Equilaterals&quot; style=&quot;width: 500px;height:375px;margin-bottom:1.625em;margin:auto;display:block;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The four equal segments of the top-left quadrant of the cake determine the symmetry of the 6 and the distance from the terminal to the degree symbol. This manner of constructing the 6 feels stable and balanced. As a result the 6 despite being heavier on its left side stays in equilibrium because of its attachment to the degree symbol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there it is - that’s how we got our logo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 11:53:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/05/19/SerendipityGeometry.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/05/19/SerendipityGeometry.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To Begin at the beginning</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What if you could update your details on your own phone, and it automatically updated all your chosen friends’ phones?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April 2003, after four years of having the most fun time of my life with my friends in college, it was finally time to say goodbye. Four years had flown by with more volleyball than engineering, and we had spent all our time in togetherness and fun, rather than in competition. Some of us were going to study further, some had a job, and some had yet to find a job. Some would stay on in the same city, some would move out, and yet others left the country to go abroad. But as they say, your friends in college are your friends for life, and it certainly felt that way to us 21-year-olds, so we never imagined that we’d ever lose touch with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the years to follow, as life moved us from one place to another and one phone number to another, and as we lost our phones and our email passwords and got busy in our own careers, we gradually lost touch with one another. So much so that today, we hardly know which of us is married, who lives where, and indeed what we all are doing with our lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did this happen? Apart from the general, tempting explanation that we were all too busy to care about each other, I believe there are specific technological, behavioral explanations too. Understanding the process of losing touch in the modern, smartphone-wielding world is the key to preventing it and solving this problem. Here are some aspects of our behaviour that I think might give us a clue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are all heavily dependent on our phones. In specific, our address books. Increasingly, our phone’s address book has come to dominate all other methods of storing our contacts – nowhere else is our entire universe of relationships more comprehensively represented. From our family to our plumber, all our connections are concentrated in our phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Our address books don’t recognize people. To our phones, our contacts are merely alphabets and numerals, with no identity. I may have a phone number under “Mom”, but my phone does not know whose contact it really is. If someone else tomorrow starts using that number after my mom gives it up, my phone will still have that number under “Mom”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We take our address books for granted. We don’t keep it updated, or well-maintained, because it’s a lot of effort to check whether each phone number, each email address and each postal address is still accurate. We often meet people twice and enter their new number or new email address under a different name, while an earlier entry may have been under a nickname.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We have no way to update others’ address books when we change our details. Sure, I could send an email to a hundred people and risk being sent straight to their spam folder. I could send free messages on Whatsapp – if my connections are there. I could send SMS messages too, except that they cost money, especially for international messages. I certainly don’t want to be putting my number up on Facebook. And they will still need to do the work of noting my number down in their phones. There is NO elegant way to let my friends know that the number under my name on their phone no longer belongs to me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 2014, losing a phone is still a death sentence to our address book. And a lot of us lose/damage our phones at some point. There are limited contacts-backup options available, but while some of them are platform-restrictive (iCloud), others are highly intrusive and often malfunction while syncing. Besides, you can’t do much else with them – they’re just a bin where you put all your contacts and keep on syncing with them for the rest of your life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how the story of 6degrees began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if you could update your details on your own phone, and it automatically updated all your chosen friends’ phones?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if, if you lost your phone, you could just buy a new phone and magically see all your contacts there – all neat and up-to-date?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if your phone could recognize people, and when many of your contacts actually refer to the same person, suggest them to you for instant merging?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s how the story of 6degrees began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S: the 6degrees website is available at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.get6degrees.com&quot;&gt;www.get6degrees.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 11:53:48 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/05/15/BeginAtBeginning.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.get6degrees.com/thoughts/2014/05/15/BeginAtBeginning.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
